{
    "id": "97bc50564e2243328b88b6658d8363a5",
    "title": "As, Since, Because, So, Due To, Owing To",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "7b325209c1e54e159c377c255671366f",
            "title": "As, Since, Because, Owing To, Due To, So",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "We stayed inside ……………. it was raining.",
                    "description": "Because of and owing to are prepositions. They are followed by nouns. Because is a conjunction. It is followed by a clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "because",
                        "because of",
                        "owing to",
                        "so"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I wanted to leave early ……………. I was not enjoying the party.",
                    "description": "The conjunctions as, since and because can all be used to refer to the reason for something. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "since",
                        "as",
                        "because",
                        "All of the above"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "The girl stayed at home ……………… her illness.",
                    "description": "Due to and owing to are interchangeable. Both of them are prepositions and are followed by nouns. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "because",
                        "due to",
                        "owing to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We were late ……………. the traffic jam.",
                    "description": "As, since and because are conjunctions. They are followed by clauses. Because of is a preposition. It is followed by a noun. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "because",
                        "because of",
                        "as",
                        "since"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She didn’t love cats ………………. she wasn’t happy when her husband bought two kittens home.",
                    "description": "The conjunctions as, since and because introduce the reason so introduces the result. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "as",
                        "so",
                        "since",
                        "because"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Ravi didn’t play …………….. his illness.",
                    "description": "Due to and owing to both mean because of.",
                    "answers": [
                        "because",
                        "owing to",
                        "due to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………. I was tired, I went to bed early.",
                    "description": "The conjunction as introduces the reason. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "As",
                        "So",
                        "Because of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She was very unhappy ……………. she missed her children.",
                    "description": "The conjunctions for and because have very similar meanings. For is common in a formal written style. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "so",
                        "because"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "………………. bad weather, we cancelled the trip.",
                    "description": "All of the given options are possible here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Due to",
                        "Owing to",
                        "Because of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………… I was having a nice time, I decided to stay longer.",
                    "description": "We use the conjunction 'as' to show the reason. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "As",
                        "So",
                        "Because of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………. it was very cold, he put on his coat.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "As",
                        "So",
                        "Because of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She couldn’t walk ……………. she had broken her leg.",
                    "description": "Because of, due to and owing to are prepositions. They cannot be followed by a clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "because",
                        "because of",
                        "due to",
                        "owing to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}